#### Contact

8588027071 (Mobile) avichalsrivastava24@gmail.c om

www.linkedin.com/in/avichalsri (LinkedIn) avichalsri.github.io/ (Portfolio)

## Top Skills

Python (Programming Language)
C (Programming Language)
C++

## Languages

Hindi (Native or Bilingual)
English (Professional Working)

### Certifications

Full Stack Development

MTA: Introduction to Programming Using Python - Certified 2019

**Business Analyst** 

Proficiency in English

**English Comprehension** 

#### Honors-Awards

Gold Medallist (10th)

Gold Medallist (12th - Chemistry)

Gold Medallist (12th - Mathematics)

Science Exhibition Winner (Tech Meet'19)

Thriftventure Winner (Tech Meet'19)

## **Publications**

Action on Google Assistant Amazon Alexa Skill

# **Avichal Srivastava**

Student Product Developer @Crio.Do || IEO'19 Finalist || Amazon Alexa and Google Assistant Skill Developer || SME @Chegg Noida

# Summary

Dynamic, Disciplined and Work-Oriented Computer Science Engineer pursuing B.Tech from NIT Manipur.

A quick efficient learner in pursuit of excellence and a motivated and ambitious individual working to achieve the unimaginable. Blue-star coder on CodeChef and having experience in the field of competitive coding.

Would be glad to be a part of your professional network...

Resume: https://bit.ly/30sOS5r

# Experience

Krayonnz (Vedarsy Technologies Pvt. Ltd.) Web Developer Intern June 2020 - Present (3 months)

Widhya
Mission Advocate
June 2020 - Present (3 months)

AnitaB.org
Python Mentor
May 2020 - Present (4 months)

GirlScript Foundation Member (The Uplift Project) May 2020 - Present (4 months)

Skillenza
Skillenza Hustler
April 2020 - Present (5 months)

Coding Blocks
Campus Ambassador

March 2020 - Present (6 months)

EventBeep
Digital Marketing Intern
May 2020 - May 2020 (1 month)

JPMorgan Chase & Co. Software Engineering Virtual Experience April 2020 - May 2020 (2 months)

Successfully Completed the JPMC's Software Engineering Virtual Experience and learnt practical implementations of the work of a Software Engineer at JPMC. Learnt the hands-on experience of software engineering in establishing Financial Data Feeds, Frontend Web Development and Data Visualization with Perspective. Perspective is an interactive visualization component for large, real-time datasets developed by JPMC.

#### Crio.Do

Product Developer Intern February 2020 - April 2020 (3 months)

Successfully completed the Crio Launch Program. Learnt the essentials of product development and worked on real-world projects. The complete journey was a great learning experience and helped me in developing my approach towards solving a problem efficiently.

Worked on 2 products: QBox (File Transfer System) and QMoney (Trading Portfolio)

## Amazon Alexa Developers

Alexa Skill Developer March 2020 - March 2020 (1 month)

Developed and deployed a skill for Amazon's virtual assistant Alexa. The skill provides the user with some of the most amazing and interesting facts about our great nation, The Incredible India.

Do check it out, just say "Alexa, open Incredible India Facts" to Alexa.

# Google Developers Action on Google Assistant

November 2019 - November 2019 (1 month)

Deployed an action on Google Assistant. The function of the action is to tell your day of birth based on your birth date. Please give it a try and review it. Say/Type "Talk to Guess My Birth Day" to the Google Assistant.

Reviews are much appreciated.

Chegg Inc.

Subject Matter Expert (CSE)
September 2019 - September 2019 (1 month)

Being the Subject Matter Expert for Computer Science and Engineering, my responsibilities included clearing student doubts, answering textbook questions as well as advanced questions related to Computer Science domain in a detailed and easy to understand manner.

Technex, IIT (BHU) Varanasi Android Application Development Intern December 2018 - December 2018 (1 month)

A one-month winter internship under Technex, IIT (BHU). The internship was based on Android Application Development under the instructor, Mr. Girish Shakya. Learned the essentials of Android Application Development with some hands-on projects.

# Education

National Institute of Technology Manipur

Bachelor of Technology - BTech, Computer Science · (2017 - 2021)

Assisi Convent School, Noida 12 Boards, PCM with C++, CBSE · (2016 - 2017)

Assisi Convent School, Noida 10 Boards, CBSE · (2014 - 2015)